<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Aegides Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.aegides.be/categories/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Aegides Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.aegides.be/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Infrastructure Project – VMware SDDC, vMotion, HA, FT, &amp; MDM</title>
      <link>https://blog.aegides.be/cloud_infrastructure_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.aegides.be/cloud_infrastructure_project/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Infrastructure Project Author: Abdullah Bagishev&#xA;Year: 2024 - 2025 Subject: VMware SDDC, vMotion, HA, FT, &amp;amp; MDM&#xA;Overview This project focuses on deploying a highly available virtualized cloud environment using VMware SDDC technologies. The setup ensures:&#xA;✅ Live VM Migration (vMotion)&#xA;✅ High Availability (HA) &amp;amp; Continuous Availability (FT)&#xA;✅ Centralized Storage with TrueNAS (iSCSI &amp;amp; Multipathing)&#xA;✅ Automated Resource Management (DRS)&#xA;✅ SSO &amp;amp; MDM (Microsoft Intune &amp;amp; Azure AD)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Hacking: Magnum Opus - LLMNR Poisoning</title>
      <link>https://blog.aegides.be/llmnr-poisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.aegides.be/llmnr-poisoning/</guid>
      <description>Ethical Hacking: Magnum Opus - LLMNR Poisoning Auteur: Abdulla Bagishev&#xA;Jaar: 2024-2025&#xA;Onderwerp: Cybersecurity en netwerkbeveiliging&#xA;Inleiding Link-Local Multicast Name Resolution (LLMNR) is een netwerkprotocol dat wordt gebruikt in Windows-netwerken om hostnamen te resolven wanneer een DNS-server niet beschikbaar is. Hoewel LLMNR functioneel waardevol is, introduceert het een significante kwetsbaarheid die kan worden misbruikt door aanvallers om gevoelige informatie te onderscheppen, zoals inloggegevens en netwerkverkeer.&#xA;In deze paper onderzoeken we hoe LLMNR-poisoning werkt en demonstreren we hoe een aanvaller de zwakheden in dit protocol kan uitbuiten.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Infrastructure Project – AWS Scalable Architecture</title>
      <link>https://blog.aegides.be/aws_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.aegides.be/aws_project/</guid>
      <description>AWS Cloud Infrastructure Project Author: Abdullah Bagishev&#xA;Year: 2024&#xA;Subject: AWS Scalable Architecture&#xA;Migrating a Monolithic Application to a Cloud-Native AWS Architecture Introduction This project was part of a Cybersecurity &amp;amp; Cloud academic assignment, where the goal was to modernize a legacy application for ACME Corp. The existing on-premises infrastructure struggled with scalability, cost-efficiency, and reliability, making it unsuitable for growing demands.&#xA;The solution? Migrating to AWS using a highly available, auto-scaled, and cost-effective architecture.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
